<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?><rss version='2.0' xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'><channel>
<title>Wiktopher</title>
<link><![CDATA[https://wiktopher.ca]]></link>
<description>Wiktopher</description>
 <image>
<url>https://wiktopher.ca/media/services/rss.jpg</url>
<title>Wiktopher — Desert tales</title>
<link>https://wiktopher.ca</link>
</image>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 15 — Lupin's Logbook</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_15.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_15.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/fauna.shadowfish.png'/>
<p>Hello Logbook. I am happy to say that Dorake's passage is a day away. Our progress is good, but slow. The wind comes and leaves as it wants, and when it's gone all we can do is wait.</p>

<p>We had such a calm this morning. In complete calms, with still sands and a clear, clear sky, it is difficult to believe that the wind will ever return. I doused the sails then, I thought it depressing to see them limp like that. I am trying to be patient, but is difficult. The Ilk doesn't have to wait for wind.</p>

<p>It is beautful out here though, calms reveals a new world. There are many plants and animals around. The plants that grow out here, like the cactub and the waterlilly, are hardy plants that can survive almost anything, unless they fall prey to a hunter. In calms they come out of the ground to take in moisture and light, and small avians run out of their hiding place to take bites out of them. The life of a desert perennial is a dangerous one. They hide during storms, and when they  surface then they must face groups of hungry, agile creatures. Many of the cactubs I've seen have leaves or nubs missing, craters in their flesh, battle scars.</p>

<p>I became familiar with the layout of the desert while traveling on the Ilk, but I did not know the fauna and flora that live in the sand, imperceptible from a distance. Eka has been teaching me. The more I learn, the better I understand the desert. I rather like learning about these things. It is comforting to know that you are never alone in the desert. There are creatures that will only ever show themselves under very specific conditions. Marvelous creatures.</p>

<p>There are reptavians flying around us now, the sound of their leathery wings evident in this quiet. I've never been good at identifying reptavians—maybe they're crested-hirudines? These ones are quick flyers, their movements jerky, and precise. In Volare we have hololomimos. Ssmall, bulgy-eyed reptavians that like to nest in houses. We didn't used to have them, we think they climbed aboard during one of our stops in Montore. They like it on the Ilk because there are plenty of shroos to eat, but of course this is a problem for my people because our food supply is limited. No one wants to harm the hololomimos, so now we have trappers that spend their time searching for nests to move them back on land. When I was last there, the relocation efforts were going well, but they always found more...</p>
<p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_15.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 14 — Tarka</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_14.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_14.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/flora.licky.png'/>
<p>That morning Lupin got up early, eager to set eyes on Tarka again after dreaming about it all night. In the dream, a tiny Verido wandered Tarka's insides, walking along bolts and nuts, hands tracing along the woodwork and meticulously inspecting the grain. Lupin wanted to spend time reading the growth lines, marking important events throughout the ages. Now, the full-sized real world version of Lupin stared at the vessel, with its patched hull, up-cycled sails, hand-woven lines... and was proud!</p>

<p>The Verido saw Maka, knees in the sand and hands deep in a bucket filled with a thick, purple substance. Beside the bucket, lay a basket of wet plurple beans. Maka had strained them to make plurple bean grease. Lupin was familiar with the process, having seen other villagers in Renate do it to use as decorative paint. The grease was thick and wet, but would fully cure after a day of full sun...</p>
<p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_14.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 13 — The Ilk Town of Balandri</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_13.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_13.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/fauna.snakadil.jpg'/>
<p>When the group arrived back in Renate, they stopped at the edge of the city, feet over an invisible grave in the sand. Many years ago, a guard from the Court Of Light had died here. Lupin and Eka did not know that this spot marked an important moment in Renzo's past, but they stopped too, mirroring their companion. A crowd gathered at the city border then, they moved toward the travelers carrying lavendiri leaves. They tossed them into the air, welcoming them back into the village.</p>

<p>Maka pushed through the crowd, rushing over and pulling Renzo into a hug. The metalworker wept. Lupin had sent the woth ahead with a message, a story of the happenings in Irideri. Maka had begun to cry then already, happy to hear that the lonely apprentice had found peace. “Not so hard!” Ren said with a laugh. A laugh, Maka couldn't believe it. Renzo never laughed, usually.</p>

<p>“Hard is all I can do, you know that!” Maka replied, speaking as curtains of tears cascaded onto the front of Ren's robes.</p>

<p>Lupin flashed Eka a smile. “All thanks to Mapoleon the woth!” Eka laughed, as the woth returned, coming to land in its glass ball. It did not respond to this name either, and started picking the dust out of its wings. "I'm beginning to think it doesn’t want to be named.” Lupin grumbled. "Mapoleon is a great name."

<p>Eka smirked, "woth doesn't agree. Woth wants what woth wants."</p>
<p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_13.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 12 — Kingdom of Irideri</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_12.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_12.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/flora.conk.shroo.jpg'/>
<p>“Things will be different, it's been 10 years," Maka said, concerned, with a hand on Iri's shoulder.</p><p>Iri’s face betrayed little emotion, as if carved from stone. “Change matters little to a specter.” Maka had been the closest thing to a mapa to this Iri, who now stood a few heads taller than the first time they'd met. Now in Iridi wear, with trimmed hair and skin devoid of grease, the apprentice was unrecognizable. The effect was so strong that Maka had asked the villagers not to come. Many in Renate still suffered from mental and emotional stress, seeing Iri like this would likely worsen their condition.</p><p>“You left your name at the gates of the city, it’s only right that you should take it back now.” Maka said.</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_12.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 11 — Tent village of Renate</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_11.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_11.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/fauna.papilion.jpg'/>
<p>Meanwhile, Lupin and Eka were walking the deserts in the near vicinity of Irideri. The mountain range encircling it had no visible openings. There were tunnels — this, they knew — but their entrances were difficult to find. There was another problem. In the event that they ever did find the tunnels, these, would likely be guarded. "SO! If the tunnels are guarded, how are WE going to get in?" Lupin asked, standing in Hush's shadow. The sun was especially hot today, but the large furry beast didn't seem to mind.</p><p>"In? No no no," Eka said, head shaking in a Nono sort-of-way. Lupin's eyes narrowed down. "Soooo, no to noodles then?"</p><p>"Yes to noodles! That hasn't changed." Eka replied, mouth watering at the very thought of food. "The monks live in a tower overlooking the city, set on the highest peak of the Andenuis. It lies just outside of Irideri, that's what Aristollo says in the book I borrowed anyway..."</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_11.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 10 — Little light</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_10.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_10.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/flora.chloromyce.shroo.jpg'/>
<p> "Irideri," Eka said, "home of the Iridi! That's where we're going next. The Iridi monks there make the BEST chloromyce shroo noodles. The noodles glow in the dark! Plus if you eat too much the soles of your feet become iridescent. Lasts about a week, it's great."</p><p>"Monks who make noodles?" Lupin said, while caressing the spot between Hush's ears. The hyroo had carried them much distance and now demanded a head massage.</p><p>"Oooh yes! At the end of every year, Iridi monks go deep underground, into the chasms of the Andenuis and spend a month there, alone, meditating. When they emerge, they prepare the noodles and eat them together to celebrate the new year. It symbolizes a renewal of the self, shedding your old skin kind of thing."</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_10.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 9 — Montore</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_09.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_09.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/fauna.durdle.jpg'/>
<p>"I really couldn't let you in, not without identification." A young Aodal said, standing behind a desk equipped with bars, as if to protect the desk clerk from physical harm. This should have given Lupin some hint as to what sort of town Montore was, a place with rules and procedures, something that can drive even the calmest of persons up a wall.</p><p>"We don't have that in Volare!" Lupin said, getting hot in the face. "I see." The clerk reached for a pamphlet and handed it over to Lupin through an opening in the bars. The pamphlet read: "So you don't exist."</p><p>"What is this?"</p><p>"If you want to exist in the eyes of Montore you need a piece of identification."</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_09.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 8 — An oasis</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_08.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_08.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/fauna.floater.jpg'/>
<p>Lupin and Eka arrived near a hollow, they did not have to come through here to go to Montore but Eka had insisted on it. This place, Nono had said, was wrought with strange creatures. They were instructed to transit quickly, but their sore feet gave them much trouble. The two experimented with walking fast, making much distance but getting tired faster, or walking slow, making little progress but with more energy to spare. When Hush was in a good mood, they would do a few long leaps ahead, this too, helped to shorten the trip. Near the hollow, Hush sighted round creatures hovering in the distance, its ears perked up, attentive to the faintest of sounds. Something was wrong, the hyroo would not move forward, fearful of the strange beings ahead. The creatures had two black points for eyes, long fluttery wings on the sides of their bodies and tiny slits for mouths.</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_08.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 7 — Skyrock</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_07.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_07.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/fauna.seshell.jpg'/>
<p>This is the tale of a lonely piece of matter, it had once been part of some other larger body but they'd since parted. There was no way to measure how much time had passed since then - which was just as well, because this didn't matter out here. The sky rock had seen much of the universe; it no longer grieved for home, nor did it fear the unknown. Contrary to what it thought, the great expanse did not inspire fear; it was soothing, everything made sense here. The celestial bodies danced with one another, a slow and unending waltz. The rock rather liked the time it had spent adrift, but then it neared the atmosphere of a yellow planet and was pulled down onto it. It lost much of its mass in the descent, but had enough to cause a great big fuss when it struck land.</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_07.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 6 — Beobug</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_06.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_06.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/fauna.woth.jpg'/>
<p> Lupin was hanging out at the local snack bar at the edge of town. Everyone had agreed to meet here later that day, so right now was all about wasting time. The owner of the town's only restaurant served the foreigner a local drink, a glass of bonan wine. Bonan wine was an alcoholic drink that people would frequently brew in Finiku villages, every place had their own recipe. It wasn't uncommon to give some of yours to a friend, or to someone of importance, the restaurant owner Javi explained.</p><p>Javi was proud of the wine produced here in Tiputa, "siri de yorala!"</p><p>"Think others in the land say this too of their wine?"</p><p>"Ora–" the restaurant owner said, "–but they be wrong!".</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_06.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 5 — Tiputa pit stop</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_05.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_05.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/fauna.pomparu.jpg'/>
<p>Tiputa, one of many towns of the Soronan desert. It is one road, with both sides lined by 5 triangular buildings, built with a slant pointing to the east, all businesses and all Finiku-owned. The road's very design suggests that you will leave almost as quickly as you have entered, with every service just a short hop away.</p><p>Tiputa is on low-lying land, tucked into a valley known for its incessant gales. Strong winds, known in these parts as 'Shriekers', pass through here every 10 days. During this time, all activity in the town stops, the flurry of sand it generates can be very damaging to one's lungs. It is because of these 'Shriekers' that none stay in town for long, most come to re-supply, or for repairs, and then take off again.</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_05.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 4 — The sandfin</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_04.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_04.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/flora.cactub.jpg'/>
<p>Eka, Lupin and Hush wandered the desert, quenching their thirst with waterstones.Hush could no longer stand any weight on its back and walked behind them, panting. They could not get to Montore fast enough, though the thought of cake and tea did offer some motivation. During the walk, Eka sang about bam cakes, listing the ingredients aloud in song. Every song ended with a solo of groans and growls, courtesy of Lupin's empty belly. "Ba-ba-ba-bam cakes! Ba-ba-ba-bam cakes!"</p><p>"Please stop singing about food." Lupin said. They'd tried to ration the teaweet bread, but Hush raided their stores in the night and all 5 loaves had already been eaten, and digested. Eka and Lupin had to suck on waterstones, it helped in the absence of food as they could draw out the water in economical doses. "We're going to die out here." Lupin said, groaning.</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_04.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 3 — Mountain with no name</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_03.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_03.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/fauna.vennec.jpg'/>
<p>Lupin marched towards the mountain, carrying a bag plump with supplies. Uno gave ample food for the difficult journey ahead. The bag contained a dozen waterstones, 5 loaves of teaweet bread and some root vegetables. The climb was difficult as there was no evident road or path to take. Lupin progressed slowly, climbing over faces of jagged rock, feet and hands finding cracks and creases for support. The Verido stopped often to eat, sleep, or to watch the world below get smaller. The mounting altitude was comforting, like being on the back of an Ilk. The sand plains stretched past the limits of Lupin's vision, this terrain was unfamiliar at ground level but was easy to recognize from up here. Their former campsite was just a few dunes west of the one resembling an Ilk's spine.</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_03.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 2 — Bed of dust</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_02.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_02.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/fauna.hyroo.jpg'/>
<p>Lupin could hear someone screaming. Was it the wind? Or was it the sound of life leaving this body? Lupin would have prefered not to know that skin and bones could scream. The sound was unbearable. The young Volarian did fear death, but didn't think that consciousness would part with the flesh in flight, contrary to what the elders in Volare believed.</p><p>Leaping from the Ilk's snout was common practice with the old and the sick of the village. All habitants of the Soronan Desert celebrated Leaping Days. Lupin always thought that it was a joyful and painless experience, but this was a beautiful lie. Lupin was afraid, and falling fast. In a panic, the brain struggled to find ways to cope with the stress...</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_02.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chapter 1 — Voice of the Ilk</title>
  <link>https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_01.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>chapter_01.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://wiktopher.ca/media/content/fauna.ilk.jpg'/>
<p>In a room, in a house, on the back of a giant, lives a Verido, a teenager whose name is a mixture of two good things: Lu, for the sky, and Pin, a type of winged beetle. "Come on Lupin, keep at it. Keep searching." Lupin said, busy upturning all objects in the house. While proud of this name, Lupin did not choose it. Verido are unique in the way that their names and lineage appear on their skin a few years after they're grown. They take on the appearance of lines, and swirls, and when interpreted by a skilled Reader, they're translated into the common tongue. These patterns are then pricked with a permanent blue colour to add emphasis.</p><p>Lupin could never remember where things were, much-needed items had a way of getting 'lost'. Worse yet, was that Lupin also liked to borrow things. All Verido borrowed from one another. If they saw something they liked in the house of another, they would take it without asking. Objects had a way of making the rounds and somehow always ended up back where they'd started — that is, unless Lupin was the borrower. Many objects from homes around the village never returned. Everyone knew who to blame, yet no one came to claim anything back, having found joy in owning fewer things.</p><p><a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_01.html'>Continue reading</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
</channel></rss>